Michael Moawad

michaelmoawad.com michaelmoawad.com

Efficient self-starter with 3 years building an exceptional foundation of knowledge and relationships in the Tech industry. Reduced time-to-value on critical new skill sets by rapidly mastering and adopting new technology stacks, frameworks, and testing tools. 5+ years of experience collaborating with cross-functional colleagues on internal and external teams.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP, Python, Bash, HTML 5, CSS **Frameworks and Databases**: React, NodeJS, jQuery, SASS, MySQL

Tools and Software: Git, Linux VPS, Magento 2, WordPress, SSH SFTP, Figma, Lighthouse, BrowserStack

Employment

Front End Developer

Architectural Association

Nov 2020 - Present

- Create React components able to retrieve and render information from live databases dynamically, allowing
 employees to independently upload content directly to site via Statamic CMS hugely reducing publishing time.
- Designed logic to map through, print data sets called from API's replacing 500+ lines of hard code across codebase.
- Process, manipulate and print pulled data using MySQL, PHP and Axios with NodeJS to access and handle JSON.
- Optimised testing by establishing strong understanding of large-scale website infrastructures allowing for quick
 discovery and ability to locate errors using Inspector, Lighthouse and other tools creating swift resolutions and fixes.

E-Commerce Developer

Cumi Ltd

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020

- Managed **Linux VPS** using **Bash**, adjusting memory allocation and other server components while maintaining the data base ensuring safety of data, processes, and server-side software during deployment of website revisions.
- Developed functional and responsive design blocks integrating HTML5, CSS3 functionality with Magento 2 CMS.
- Boosted website load speeds through optimising asset delivery using caching, compression and more.

Website Developer

Coptic Lawvers Worldwide

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

- Designed UI and UX of the site and built using React Styled components to mitigate repeated code with focus on responsiveness and event handling using CSS grid in conjunction with Flex and media queries.
- Addressed production bugs and improvements requested by team using **Kanban** to prioritize tasks while implementing **CI/CD pipelines** to speedily deploy and iterate through new website versions.

Relevant Experience and Projects

Bible Reader Web App React, Axios, CSS Flex

https://biblereader.netlify.app/

React project utilising data fetching and parsing from external API's using state management and React Hooks as well as declarative routing between pages using React Router. Responsive styling using CSS Flex and Parallax Website design.

Roll the Dice App JavaScript, HTML, CSS

http://roll-the-dice-game.netlify.app/

Vanilla JavaScript Budget Management application calculating total income and expenses input by the user. Built using no libraries and with knowledge of Lexical Scoping and Closures.

Budget App JavaScript, HTML, CSS

http://budget-app-mm.netlify.app/

Vanilla JavaScript Browser Game developed using event handlers along with other **DOM Manipulation** techniques to roll two dice, generate and reset scores and terminate the game once a player has won.

Education

University of Southampton BEng (Hons) in Mechanical Engineering. 2:1

Sep 2015 | Jun 2018

Additional Achievements

Music: Gained over 2 million streams with over 800 thousand monthly listeners and was placed on Spotify editorial playlists for tracks I wrote, recorded, produced, and mixed while building relationships with industry professionals. **Charity**: Co-Organiser for Coptic City Mission Fundraisers and Christmas parties, leading worship music and distributing foods and goods. Victoria, London.